<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' standalone='no'?>
<doxygen xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="compound.xsd" version="1.8.14">
  <compounddef id="_internal_component_design" kind="page">
    <compoundname>InternalComponentDesign</compoundname>
    <title>Internal Component Design</title>
    <briefdescription>
    </briefdescription>
    <detaileddescription>
<sect1 id="_internal_component_design_1InternalComponentDesign">
<title>Internal Component Design</title>
<para>The component is splitted into the follwing SW units:<itemizedlist>
<listitem><para>ErrHdl_Can_bus_Enable_condition - This is responsible for set/reset of enable condition of standard can and tDiagStartT</para></listitem><listitem><para>ErrHdl_Can_Bus_off_Detection - This is responsible for checking bus off condition and setting the related DTC.</para></listitem><listitem><para>ErrHdl_Can_Global_Timeout_Detection - This unit is responsible for monitoring Global timeout and than set/reset the corresponding DTC.</para></listitem><listitem><para>ErrHdl_Can_Single_Wire_Detection - This unit is responsible for monitoring Single wire error and than set/reset the corresponding DTC.</para></listitem><listitem><para>ErrHdl_Can_Vlan_Node_Timeouts_Detection - Responsible for checking if timeout has occured on each node and set the DTC. It also has an API to reset timeout when message is received.</para></listitem><listitem><para>ErrHdl_Can_Vlan_Nodes_Enable_Condition - Responsible for enable condition when MFL node is coded.</para></listitem><listitem><para>ErrHdl_Channel_Operation_Cycle - Cyclically checks for bus state change and handles operating cycles DTC of CAN, LIN nad remote CANS</para></listitem><listitem><para>ErrHdl_Dataset - Responsible to sets data set invalid DTCs at start of ICAS life cycle.</para></listitem><listitem><para>ErrHdl_DEM_Event_Map_Arrays - Provides node timemout DEM event ID.</para></listitem><listitem><para>ErrHdl_DEM_Interface - provides interface between Error handler and DEM component to set/reset DTC or enable condition. <linebreak/>
</para></listitem><listitem><para>ErrHdl_DK2_Can_Timeout_Detection - Responsible for DK2 node timeout DTCs and enable condition.</para></listitem><listitem><para>ErrHdl_DTC_State_To_DLI - Responsible to notify DLI Library about state of timeout DTCs.</para></listitem><listitem><para>ErrHdl_Ethernet_Communication - Responsible to inform that the eletrical fault occurred,Timeout occured,MAC address conflicts on ethernet bus.</para></listitem><listitem><para>ErrHdl_High_Temperature - Responsible to monitor high temperature errors.</para></listitem><listitem><para>ErrHdl_If - Provides an interface between BuiltInList and error handler. It is used to notify error handler that rebuild has taken place or new message is received, and than handling of DTC.</para></listitem><listitem><para>ErrHdl_Lin_Electrical_Failure_Detection - Handles setting/reseting LIN electrical failure DTC according to given Status</para></listitem><listitem><para>ErrHdl_Lin_Enable_Conditions - Responsible for setting LIN node, bus, or Lin global timeout enable condition.</para></listitem><listitem><para>ErrHdl_Lin_Frame_Errors_Detection - Cyclically monitors LIN node timeout and global timeout error, and set the corresponding error.</para></listitem><listitem><para>ErrHdl_Reset_Counter - Responsible for clearing/writing unexpected resets counter value to NVM when new data is available.</para></listitem><listitem><para>ErrHdl_Start_Diag_Timer - Responsible for counting Diag timer, KL15 timer, KL30 timer. and reset the timer if state changes from off to on.</para></listitem><listitem><para>ErrHdl_Steuergeraet_Defekt - Responsible to check if Steuergeraet Error DTC should be set to active and also responsible to reset flag which indicate that any of Steuergeraet DTC is currently handled.</para></listitem><listitem><para>ErrHdl_Voltage_Out_Of_Range_Error - Responsible to handle battery out of range errors and also to chose appropriate DTCs and DEM condition state based on VoltageRange.</para></listitem><listitem><para>ErrHdl_Vlan_Bus_Port_Enable_Condition - Cyclically monitors Vlan bus status. If bus state is active than set enable condition and reset the diag timer.</para></listitem><listitem><para>ErrHdl - Responsible for providing cyclic task for other error handler unit.</para></listitem></itemizedlist>
</para></sect1>
<sect1 id="_internal_component_design_1SW">
<title>Requirements Allocation</title>
<para>The component covers requirement present in the module 5.SWR_ICAS1_BSW. The requirements present in chapter 2.18.2 Network Diagnostics and 2.18.6 Diagnostic Trouble Codes is covered by this component. The <bold>Requirements traceability</bold> in SWA can be found in EA in the following location:<linebreak/>
VW_ICAS1.Chorus.All_Cores.SoftwareDecomposition.ComplexDeviceDrivers.ECU_DIAG_Chorus.ErrHdl_MQB.SW Architecture.SW Requirements.Requirements traceability traceability</para></sect1>
<sect1 id="_internal_component_design_1SoftwareUnitInterfaces">
<title>Software Unit Interfaces</title>
<para>There is interface between ErrHdl and other software unit in this component. ErrHdl provides cyclic task to other software unit. <linebreak/>
The ErrHdl_Can_bus_Enable_condition provides an interface (ErrSetCanGlobalTimeoutDEMCond) to <ref refid="_err_hdl___if_8c" kindref="compound">ErrHdl_if.c</ref> sets Can global timeout enable condition when at least one node is coded on bus.<linebreak/>
ErrHdl_Can_Global_Timeout_Detection provides interface <ref refid="group___l_i_s_t___o_f___p_u_b_l_i_c___i_n_t_e_r_f_a_c_e_s_1gab034569e861b326a93261d9ae8bc1aeb" kindref="member">ErrIsCanGlobalTimeoutAllowed()</ref> to ErrHdl_Can_bus_Enable_condition to check if global timemout is allowed.<linebreak/>
ErrHdl_Can_Bus_off_Detection provides interface (ErrIsBusOffCounterGreaterThanZero) to ErrHdl_Can_Global_Timeout_Detection and ErrHdl_Can_Vlan_Node_Timeouts_Detection to check if bussoff error has occured. <linebreak/>
ErrHdl_Can_Vlan_Node_Timeouts_Detection provides an interface ErrResetNodeTimeoutCounterAndDTC to reset DTC and timer when new message is received used by ErrHdl_if, ErrGetNumOfCodedNodesOnBus to check the number of coded nodes and ErrGetBillIndexFromErrCodedNodesArr to get index of nodes, used by Global timeout detection and VLAN bus port enable condition. <linebreak/>
ErrHdl_DEM_Event_Map_Arrays provides an interface (ErrGetNodeTimeoutDEMEventId) used to get DEM event ID of node timeout which is used by ErrHdl_Can_Vlan_Node_Timeouts_Detection.<linebreak/>
ErrHdl_If provides interface (ErrGetBusState) to other Error handler to check bus state.<linebreak/>
ErrHdl_DEM_Interface provides interface between Error handler and DEM component to set/reset DTC or enable condition. <linebreak/>
ErrHdl_Slaves_Defect_Detection is used to monitor if DK2 built in list rebuild takes place. and also to handle DK2 DTC. <linebreak/>
ErrHdl_Start_Diag_Timer provides interface<itemizedlist>
<listitem><para>ErrTDiagStartTKL15HasElapsed to get the status of KL15 Diag timer, which is used by ErrHdl_Can_Global_Timeout_Detection and ErrHdl_Can_Vlan_Node_Timeouts_Detection.</para></listitem><listitem><para>ErrTDiagStartTKL30HasElapsed to get the status of KL30 Diag timer, which is used by ErrHdl_Can_Global_Timeout_Detection, ErrHdl_Can_Vlan_Node_Timeouts_Detection, ErrHdl_Can_bus_Enable_condition and ErrHdl_Lin_Enable_Conditions.</para></listitem><listitem><para>ErrResetTDiagStartT to reset Diag timer, which is used by ErrHdl_Can_bus_Enable_condition, ErrHdl_DEM_Interface, ErrHdl_Lin_Enable_Conditions</para></listitem></itemizedlist>
</para><para>ErrHdl_Can_Bus_off_Detection provides (ErrSetResetCanBusOffCounter) external interface to BusMonitorConfig to check if Bus off failed has occured.<linebreak/>
ErrHdl_If provides an external interface between Built in list component and Error handler component. It is used to get information when message in received, solverbau or node list is updated.<linebreak/>
ErrHdl_Lin_Electrical_Failure_Detection provides a external interface to set DTC when LIN electrical failure is detected.<linebreak/>
ErrHdl_Lin_Enable_Conditions provides an interface to GW_SollvSubbTeiln to set LIN enable condition.<linebreak/>
ErrHdl_Reset_Counter provides a interface to DiagAppl_DCM_Service14 to update reset counter value when SID 14 is requested.</para></sect1>
<sect1 id="_internal_component_design_1SoftwareUnitInteraction">
<title>Software Unit Interaction</title>
<para>The below diagram depicts the interaction between each Error handler unit.<linebreak/>
<image type="html" name="ErrHdl_1.png"></image>
 </para><para><image type="html" name="ErrHdl_2.png"></image>
 </para><para><image type="html" name="ErrHdl_3.png"></image>
 </para><para><image type="html" name="ErrHdl_4.png"></image>
 </para><para><image type="html" name="ErrHdl_5.png"></image>
 </para><para><image type="html" name="ErrHdl_6.png"></image>
 </para></sect1>
<sect1 id="_internal_component_design_1SoftwareUnitDescription_1">
<title>Dynamic Behavior</title>
<para>The interaction of Module can be divided into following steps: <linebreak/>
 <bold>Interraction with the start-up code.</bold> <image type="html" name="ErrorHandler_Startup.png"></image>
 </para><para><bold>The interaction digaram is related to check condition for CAN enable condition and Vlan enable condition.There is also condition set/reset DTC for single wire. </bold> <image type="html" name="Software_Unit_Interaction_Can_Bus_enable_condition.png"></image>
 </para><para><bold>The interaction digaram is related to set/reset DTC for Busoff, Global Timeout. </bold> <image type="html" name="Software_Unit_Interaction_Can_global_timeout_condition.png"></image>
 </para><para><bold> This sequence diagram is related to clearing global timeout and Node timeout when message is received </bold> <image type="html" name="BIL_UPDATE_ERROR.png"></image>
 </para><para><bold> This interaction diagram is related to handling single wire DTCs. </bold> <image type="html" name="Software_Unit_Interaction_Single_wire.png"></image>
 </para><para><bold>This interaction diagram is related to timeout of individual node. </bold> <image type="html" name="Software_Unit_Interaction_Can_Vlan_node.png"></image>
 </para><para><bold>This interaction diagram is related to Enable condition for MFL node. </bold> <image type="html" name="Software_Unit_Interaction_Can_Vlan_node_enable.png"></image>
 </para><para><bold>This interaction diagram is related to reseting of node DTC and network diagnostic DTC when built in list rebuild or code change takes place. </bold> <image type="html" name="Software_Unit_Interaction_ErrHdl_If.png"></image>
 </para><para><bold>This interaction diagram is related to DK2 node timeout detection and LIN enable conditions </bold> <image type="html" name="Software_Unit_Interaction_ErrHdl_Dk2_Can_Timeout_detection.png"></image>
 </para><para><bold>This interaction diagram is related to error handler reset counter </bold> <image type="html" name="reset_counter.png"></image>
 </para><para><bold>Checks if DK2 builtinlist rebuild has taken place. When condition is set DTC will be handled. </bold> <image type="html" name="DK2_DTC_handling.png"></image>
 </para><para><bold>Used for KL30 and KL15 tDiagStartT timers calculations </bold> <image type="html" name="tDiagStartT_timer.png"></image>
 </para><para><bold>The interaction digaram is related to set/reset DTC for Bus state change (CAN/LIN/MFL node) </bold> <image type="html" name="Software_Unit_Interaction_Channel_Operation_Cycle.png"></image>
 </para><para><bold>The interaction digaram is related to set data set invalid DTCs at start of ICAS life cycle </bold> <image type="html" name="Software_Unit_Interaction_ErrHdl_Dataset.png"></image>
  <bold>The interaction digaram is related to set data set invalid DTCs at start of ICAS life cycle </bold> <image type="html" name="Software_Unit_Interaction_ErrHdl_Voltage_Out_Of_Range_Error.png"></image>
 </para><para><bold>The interaction digaram is related to notify DLI Library about state of timeout DTCs. </bold> <image type="html" name="Software_Unit_Interaction_ErrHdl_DTC_State_To_DLI.png"></image>
 </para><para><bold> The interaction digaram is related to notify DLI Library about state of timeout DTCs. </bold> <image type="html" name="Software_Unit_Interaction_ErrHdl_DTC_State_To_DLI.png"></image>
 </para><para>The interaction digaram is related to monitor high temperature errors <image type="html" name="Software_Unit_Interaction_ErrHdl_High_Temperature.png"></image>
 </para><para><bold> The interaction digaram is related check if Steuergeraet Error DTC should be set to active </bold> <image type="html" name="Software_Unit_Interaction_ErrHdl_Steuergeraet_Defekt.png"></image>
 </para><para><bold>The interaction digaram is related to Ethernetcommunication </bold> <image type="html" name="Software_Unit_Interaction_ErrHdl_Ethernet_Communication.png"></image>
 </para><para><bold>This interaction diagram is related to interaction between </bold> <bold>- ErrHdl_DEM_Interface and external component </bold> <bold>- ErrHdl_DK2_Can_Timeout_Detection and external component </bold> <bold>- ErrHdl_Lin_Electrical_Failure_Detection and external component </bold></para><para><image type="html" name="Software_Unit_Interaction_External.png"></image>
 </para></sect1>
<sect1 id="_internal_component_design_1SoftwareUnitDescription_2">
<title>Data flow Diagram</title>
<para>The diagram below presents the major dataflow from the module.<linebreak/>
 <image type="html" name="ErrHdl_DataFlow_1.png"></image>
 </para><para><image type="html" name="ErrHdl_DataFlow_2.png"></image>
 </para><para><image type="html" name="ErrHdl_DataFlow_3.png"></image>
 </para><para><heading level="2">Tasks</heading>
</para><para>The component Error Handler provides interface that is called cyclically by OSTask &quot;ErrHandlerTask&quot; (period = 10ms). The monitoring of error take place cyclically here. see also Interaction Diagram of Error handler cyclic at the following location in Enterprise Architect: VW_ICAS1.Chorus.All_Cores.SoftwareDecomposition.ComplexDeviceDrivers.ECU_DIAG_Chorus.ErrHdl_MQB.SW Architecture.Dynamic <heading level="2">Interrupts</heading>
</para><para>There is no interrupts directly handled by Error handler. <heading level="2">Events</heading>
</para><para>there is 2 events in Error Handler ErrStartEv - During start of a event and ErrCyclicEv - cyclic event called every 10ms. <heading level="2">Operating Modes</heading>
</para><para>Operation modes are used by DTCs and network diagnoses. Each bus has his own operation cycle.<itemizedlist>
<listitem><para>New operation cycle is started when bus change state from inactive to active.</para></listitem><listitem><para>Operation cycle ends when bus change state from active to inactive.</para></listitem></itemizedlist>
</para><para><heading level="2">Power Modes</heading>
</para><para>The component need to work in the following power modes:<itemizedlist>
<listitem><para>under voltage is below 5500.</para></listitem><listitem><para>Normal voltage between 5500+500 to 18500-500.</para></listitem><listitem><para>over volatge is above 18500.</para></listitem></itemizedlist>
</para><para>As it need to set DTC during under voltage and over voltage. <linebreak/>
 <heading level="2">Exception and Error Handling</heading>
</para><para>The Error Handling is explained in Dynamic Behavior. <heading level="2">Synchronization</heading>
</para><para>Since the component is designed to run on a single core, In the case where data needs to be shared to other cores, RTE_LIGHT is used.</para><para><heading level="2">Operations</heading>
</para><para>See function list.</para><para><heading level="2">Macros</heading>
</para><para>See the macro list.</para><para><heading level="2">Algorithms</heading>
</para><para>Not applicable.</para><para><heading level="2">Data Structures</heading>
</para><para>See the structure list.</para></sect1>
<sect1 id="_internal_component_design_1SoftwareDesignEval">
<title>Evaluate Software Detailed Design</title>
<para><table rows="7" cols="3"><row>
<entry thead="yes"><para>Attribute  </para></entry><entry thead="yes"><para>Value  </para></entry><entry thead="yes"><para>Rational   </para></entry></row>
<row>
<entry thead="no"><para>Interoperability  </para></entry><entry thead="no"><para>Medium  </para></entry><entry thead="no"><para>To set DTC function are used to send data between unit   </para></entry></row>
<row>
<entry thead="no"><para>Interaction  </para></entry><entry thead="no"><para>High  </para></entry><entry thead="no"><para>number of dependencies from dependency diagram is greater than or equal to 7   </para></entry></row>
<row>
<entry thead="no"><para>Criticality  </para></entry><entry thead="no"><para>Low  </para></entry><entry thead="no"><para>Not ASIL and not a stack and not new and intraction is rated low   </para></entry></row>
<row>
<entry thead="no"><para>Technical complexity  </para></entry><entry thead="no"><para>High  </para></entry><entry thead="no"><para>Interaction &gt; Medium   </para></entry></row>
<row>
<entry thead="no"><para>Risks  </para></entry><entry thead="no"><para>High  </para></entry><entry thead="no"><para>number of SW units &gt;=5.   </para></entry></row>
<row>
<entry thead="no"><para>Testability  </para></entry><entry thead="no"><para>High  </para></entry><entry thead="no"><para>Testable completely on SWATT.   </para></entry></row>
</table>
</para><para><linebreak/>
</para><para><linebreak/>
</para><para><linebreak/>
</para><para><linebreak/>
</para><para><linebreak/>
</para><para><linebreak/>
</para><para><linebreak/>
</para></sect1>
    </detaileddescription>
  </compounddef>
</doxygen>
